thinkswap.com 2018-09-06

# Privacy Policy | Thinkswap

This Privacy Policy applies to the activities of Thinkswap Pty Ltd (ACN 145 082 739) ("Thinkswap"). It explains how Thinkswap handles personal information and complies with the requirements of the Privacy Act 1988. If you have further questions relating to this policy, please contact [admin@thinkswap.com.au](mailto:admin@thinkswap.com.au).

Thinkswap recognises the importance of your privacy and that you have a right to control how your personal information is collected and used.

**Collecting information about you:**

Thinkswap collects personal information from customers, employees, contractors, shareholders and other individuals. We collect this information when it is necessary for business purposes.

The main types of information Company collects are the contact details of customers or people who use the Thinkswap website such as email address, name, address, date of birth and gender.

We collect most of this information directly from individuals when we deal with them, such as when they register as a user of our website. The personal information we collect may be provided on forms filled out by individuals, during face-to-face meetings, in email messages, during telephone conversations, or by third parties. If you contact us, we may keep a record of that contact.

We sometimes use cookie technology on our website to provide information and services to website visitors. Cookies are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard-disk for record keeping purposes and are a necessary part of facilitating online transactions. They are also useful to determine overall traffic patterns through our website. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. If you do not wish to receive any cookies, you may set your browser to refuse cookies, but this may mean you will not be able to take full advantage of the services on the website.

Employee records are not generally subject to the Privacy Act and this Privacy Policy does not apply to our handling of such records to the extent that such records are not subject to the Privacy Act. For information about our practices relating to employee information, please contact us directly.

**Using and disclosing your personal information:**

Our purpose in collecting information about you is to provide you with services that you request and to operate our business efficiently. We do not routinely disclose personal information to third parties, except to certain companies for the purposes of sending you marketing in respect of products or services that you may be interested in but only where you have given Thinkswap permission to be contacted by those companies or by us.

We will not use or disclose any personal information about you without your consent, unless:

  * required by law
  * it is permitted by this Privacy Policy
  * we believe it necessary to provide you with goods or services you have requested
  * it is necessary to implement our terms of service
  * it is necessary to protect the rights, property or personal safety of a Thinkswap employee, another Thinkswap customer, or any member of the public or Thinkswap
  * some or all of the assets and operations of the business are or may be transferred to another party by way of sale of some or all of Thinkswap’s business.

Like many businesses, we use a range of service providers to help us maximize the quality and efficiency of our services and our business operations. This means that individuals and organizations outside of Thinkswap, such as independent contractors and consultants, off-site security storage providers, website hosts, mail-houses, electronic database managers, event managers, credit managers and debt collecting agencies, will sometimes have access to personal information held by Thinkswap and may use it on behalf of Thinkswap. We require our service providers to adhere to strict privacy guidelines and not to keep this information or use it for any unauthorised purposes. We may also share non-personal, de-identified and aggregated information for research or promotional purposes.

If Thinkswap staff obtain products or services offered by a third party pursuant to an agreement or arrangement between that third party and Thinkswap, such as a credit card provider, we may provide your personal information to that third party service provider, including information that relates to your use of such services.

If we collect or use personal information in ways other than as stated in this Privacy Policy, we will do so in accordance with the requirements of the Privacy Act.

**Using your personal information for marketing:**

We may use personal information you have provided to us, including your email address, to advise you, either directly or through a third party, of new or updated products or services or special offers or promotions that you may be interested in.

If at any time you do not wish to receive such information from us, you may ask us to remove your name from our list by emailing us at [admin@thinkswap.com.au](mailto:admin@thinkswap.com.au). Alternatively, if we send you such information by email, you can use the unsubscribe function in the email to inform us that you do not wish to receive such information from us by email. In either case, please allow 28 days for your request to be processed.

**Access to your personal information:**

Upon request, we will provide you with access to personal information we hold about you, except in the limited circumstances in which it is permitted for us to withhold this information.

When you make a request to access personal information, we will require you to provide some form of identification so we can verify that you are the person to whom the information relates. In some cases, we may also request an administrative fee to cover the costs of access. Our file of your information will usually be made available to you within 14 days.

If at any time you wish to change personal information that we hold about you because it is inaccurate or out-of-date, please contact us by emailing us at [admin@thinkswap.com.au](mailto:admin@thinkswap.com.au) and we will amend this information. If you wish to have your personal information deleted, please contact us and we will take all reasonable steps to delete it unless we need to keep it for legal, auditing or internal risk reasons.

**Storage and security of your personal information:**

Thinkswap will endeavour to take all reasonable steps to keep secure any information that we hold about you, whether electronically or in hard copy, and to keep this information accurate and up-to-date. If we hold your information electronically, it will be stored on secure servers that are protected in controlled facilities. We may also store some of the information in Thinkswap’s customer relationship management system. We require our employees and data processors to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by Thinkswap.

Thinkswap may use overseas facilities to process or back-up its information. As a result, we may transfer your personal information to our overseas facilities for storage or processing. However, this does not change any of our commitments to safeguard your privacy.

**What to do if you  have a question:**

If Thinkswap becomes aware of any ongoing concerns or problems concerning our privacy practices, we will take these issues seriously and work to address these concerns. If you have any further queries relating to our Privacy Policy, or you have a problem or complaint, please contact us at [admin@thinkswap.com.au](mailto:admin@thinkswap.com.au).

**Changes to our Privacy Policy:**

Our commitment to being a leading provider of knowledge services means that our business will continue to evolve as we respond to customer needs. Because of this, our policies will be reviewed and may be revised from time to time. Thinkswap reserves the right to change its Privacy Policy at any time. We will post any updated versions of our Privacy Policy on our website. The amended Privacy Policy will apply between us whether or not we have given you specific notice of any change.

**Use of password:**

You can also play an important role in keeping your personal information secure by maintaining the confidentiality of any password and accounts used on the Company website. Please notify us immediately if there is any unauthorized use of your account by any other Internet user or any other breach of security. For the purposes of viewing our website you will be supplied with a user name and password. You are responsible for the security of your password and login information. You take responsibility to ensure the confidentiality of this information. Please note in considering your user name, that this name will be associated with any User Content you may contribute to the site.

**Links:**

Thinkswap provides links to websites outside of the Company service. These linked sites are not under the control of Thinkswap, and we are not responsible for the conduct of companies linked to our website. Before disclosing your personal information on any other website, we advise you to examine the Terms and Conditions of those websites.
